

Leon Mutiso K.

- SOFTWARE ENGINEER / CREATIVE DIRECTOR -

INTRODUCTION

I am a creative problem-solver, outgoing, ready to learn and grow in whatever I do.
I have a bachelor's degree in Film Production and Animation but I have worked in companies in different sectors. Most notably, Andela, one of the best tech companies in the USA, as a software engineer (self-taught).

EXPERIENCE

Creative and Motion Graphics Executive

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

Scope Markets

0

In charge of the company brand & Marketing content to ensure all content, design & landing website pages are in line with the company's brand guidelines across all offices (Kenya, South Africa, Vietnam, Nigeria, Belize, Nigeria & Shangai).

Independent Consultant

2019 - 2020

Develop Rest APIs and Websites that help handle automation for clients.

Technical skills: JavaScript, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, React, Jest, Enzyme, Travis CI, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes.

Product Coordinator

Jan 2019 - Oct 2019

Andela

0

0

0

Led a team comprising of software engineers and designers and together we built:

• A Google Maps integrated Slack application for Andelans to request and manage cab transportation across the different Andela locations - Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda, Nigeria, Egypt, Ghana, and New York.

(Full Stack Developer) Javascript & Python

Jul 2018 - Oct 2019

Andela

Specialised in Python and JavaScript programming languages. Built internal products to help ease processes and management of staff activities.

EDUCATION

MULTIMEDIA UNIVERSITY

2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Film Production and Animation

Second Class Upper

MOI FORCES ACADEMY

2010 - 2019

Secondary/High School Education

Kenya Cerificate of Seconday Education (KSCE) Grade A-

9

NAIROBI



+254 717 66 55 93



kiokoleon@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/leonkioko

SKILLS

| Professional

TypeScript/Node/Express

REACT

ExpressJS & Sequelize

Python Flask & Django

GraphQL

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE

| Personal

CREATIVITY
TEAMWORK
FLEXIBLE